Erik Kimsey Software Engineer

Email kimseyerik@gmail.com Website erikkimsey.github.io Phone 540-278-4525 Github github.com/erikkimsey

Creative software engineer with 4 years of professional experience.

Technologically agnostic. Over 5 years of experience in roles of leadership.

Entrepreneurially-minded, artistically-spirited.

Bubbling passion for developing dynamic, beautiful, and intuitive user-interfaces.

HIGHLIGHTS

- Javascript / Typescript Node.js / Express.js
- React
- React Native
- Angular
- SCSS
- SQL
- Unity3D
- C#

EDUCATION

LAMBDA SCHOOL

Software Engineering

2018 - 2019

Accelerated, intensive software engineering

- Modern full-stack web development,
- Software architecture,
- Engineering / language paradigms,
- Algorithms / data structures,
- Responsive / Mobile-first UI development,
- Authentication / authorization,
- Database and REST API development.

OREGON STATE U.

Post-Bacc Computer Science

2016 - 2017

- Accelerated Object-Oriented Programming,
- C++,
- Vim,
- Discrete Mathematics.

BLUE RIDGE CC

Graphic / UI Design Certificate

2014 - 2015

Principles of graphic design and web

- Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign
- Graphic and UI design fundamentals,
- Color theory.

James Madison University Philosophy, Studio Art, Creative Writing

2006 - 2010

Phi Sigma Tau Honors Society

VOLUNTEER

HARRISONBURG RESCUE SQUAD

FMT-B

2012-2013

Diagnose and administer requisite medical attention on patients enroute to hospital.

EXPERIENCE

Lead Engineer (Unity3D, C#)

Moxie

2021 - Current

Moxie is a 3Dmobile application whose purpose is to provide therapeutic benefits to users suffer from social anxiety. Therein, my responsibilities included:

- developing concept prototypes for iOS devices using appropriate technology,
- designing UI / UX and creating respective assets (i.e., 2D graphics, 3D models, audio assets),
- designing and developing Moxie's backend for housing user-data,
- researching business and marketing plans.

LEAD UI ENGINEER

University of Virginia / Sartography

2020 - 2021

SkillSTAR is an experimental mobile application, used to research the efficacy of educational paradigms on children with autism. My responsibilities were to:

- architect and developed the alpha-version of SkillSTAR,
- implement the "CHAIN" learning algorithm,
- insure SkillSTAR met usability requirements for specific end-user needs.

FULL-STACK ENGINEER

Chatwise

2019 - 2020

Chatwise was a concept, funded by Sid Viswanathan, whose purpose was to provide Blinkist-esque reading material to users through Facebook's Messenger API.

REACT NATIVE DEVELOPER

Realm

2019

Realm's mobile application is an extension of their online, "gamer"-focused social media platform.

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

NextLevel

2018

NextLevel is a contractor in Stuttgart, DEU, for whom

- build an application which would procedurally produce variations on a guilloche that B612 had designed for use on Kardion's landing site and cardstock,
- build Kardion's landing site, to later implement the above guilloche.

JAVASCRIPT ENGINEER

ChartIQ

2016 - 2017

ChartIQ develops a financial charting library. At ChartIQ, my responsibilities included:

- developing and debugging features for the ChartIQ's flagship charting library, using Javascript, HTML Canvas,
- implementing the ChartlQ library into an AngularJS application for EToro's "ProCharts" feature.